SRINATH TUMMALA

Junior Data Scientist

Email-ID: Srinathtummala7@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 75699 74666

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a dedicated working professional with one year experience in Data Science Domain. Through my master's, I have gained fundamental knowledge on Python, Machine Learning and Database technologies. During my tenure at work, I have worked on projects which involve Data collection, Data annotation, training and building Al models. I have seen myself grow as an individual demonstrating proactive approaches, better problem-solving skills and a keen eye for detail while working on the tasks assigned to me. I have consistently exceeded expectations in delivering high-quality work within deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Scientist

July 2022 - Present

OnPassive Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad, India

- Worked on various projects like Speech translation modules, speaker diarization, Spell Correction feature in Grammar check, and Text extraction using OCR by training object detection module using YOLOv5. Currently working on EKYC feature which involves face recognition, Liveliness detection, and OCR modules.
- · Gained hands-on experience in creating APIs using FAST API.

Data Science Intern

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

OnPassive Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad, India

- · Data collection, cleaning and pre-processing to build a machine learning model for email category classification project.
- Created interfaces to demonstrate projects using Streamlit application.

EDUCATION

Advanced Certification Program

June 2023 - Present

International Institute of Information Technology, Bangalore

Specialization: Machine Learning and Deep Learning

Master of Science (M.Sc) in Data Science

Oct 2020 - July 2022

Gitam University, Hyderabad

Key Courses: Python, Machine learning, Cloud Computing, Databases, Artificial Intelligence.

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc) in Computer Science

June 2017 - Sep 2020

Bhavan's Vivekananda College, Hyderabad

Key Courses: Mathematics, Statistics, Computer Science.

MASTER THESIS

Malicious URL Detection using Machine Learning

GITAM University, Hyderabad, India

March 2022

- The aim of this project is to classify a URL as a Malicious or Benign URL.
- Collected a public dataset that consists of 450176 rows and two classes of URLs: Malicious or Benign. Have extracted a total of 17 features which consist of Lexical features, count-based features, and two binary features.
- Trained the model on Adaboost and Random Forest classifiers and used the Voting Classifier ensembling method to get the optimum result among the two classifiers.

PROJECTS

One Stop App

Feb 2018

Bhavan's Vivekananda College, Hyderabad, India

- The ONE-STOP App is a solution for mobile phones with less storage space which consists of quickly accessible links to widely used applications.
- Implementation: Android Studio using Java and XML.

Bhavan's Vivekananda College App

May 2018

Bhavan's Vivekananda College, Hyderabad, India

- This app is designed to make information easily accessible for college students.
- Implementation: Android Studio using Java, XML, and SQLite database.

HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Scholarship

July 2022

GITAM University, Hyderabad, India

· Received a merit scholarship from the university for my academic performance during my master's.

Award

Dec 2019

Bhavan's Vivekananda College, Hyderabad, India

• Awarded as "Mr. Computer Genius 2019" for my achievements and projects in Computer Science in my college, within a pool of 7 other students.

Prize

Dec 2018

Bhavan's Vivekananda College, Hyderabad, India

· Received Second prize for One-Stop app among other 15 teams on Charles Babbage Day Celebrations in the college.

CORE COMPENTENCIES

Programming Languages : Python, C, C++, Java

Python-toolboxes : NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Keras, Matplotlib, OCR, Easy-OCR

Data Visualisation Tools : Microsoft Excel, Power BI
Database Technologies : SQL, NOSQL, MONGODB

Scripting Language : HTML5, XML

IDEs : Android Studio, Anaconda Miscellaneous : Latex, MS Office Suite